BHAGWATI PRASAD BAHUGUNA

PROFILE

14+ years of experience in Business development, Presales (RFP/EOI/RFE/RFQ) Tendering & liaison with Gov Bodies. Business ideation, Marketing Communication, BTL/ATL, Product Launch, Activation, **Tendering Processes & Account** Management. Experience in working with IT / ITES organizations along with varied industries and domains across the globe that include Consumer Electronics, Retail & Lifestyle Retail to name a few. Strong sales process knowledge, effective pipeline management techniques. Have demonstrated & verifiable track record of achieving or exceeding sales quota in previous organizations.

CONTACT

PHONE: (+91) 7011878234

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/भगवती-प्रसाद-बहुगुणा-37288b14

EMAIL: bpbahuguna@gmail.com

CURRENT LOCATION: Dehradun (UK)

TOP SKILLS

Marketing Communication
Business Development
Presales
Sharp Eye for Detail
Market Research
Client Acquisition & Retention
Outcome Focussed Leader
Persistent Problem Solver

WORK EXPERIENCE

ICHHAPURTI.COM (GGJ SOLUTIONS PVT LTD) AREA SALES MANAGER JULY 2021 - APR 2022

- -Acting as Brand Custodian for Ichhapurti.com in the assigned region.
- -Franchise Selling
- -Develop / Appoint new FMCG dealers to expand product reach in the

market working in close interaction with the dealer's distributors to assist them to promote the product.

-Channel Development in the assigned territory – FMCG Distributor & New/Existing Kirana Dealer Scouting, On-Boarding, Development & Nurturing of

the Distributor-Dealer network.

- -Identify Develop new streams for revenue growth and maintain relationships with customers.
- -Analyze review the market response/ requirements communicating the same to the marketing teams for coming up with new launches
- -Establishing, maintaining and expanding your dealer base. Increasing business opportunities through various routes to market
- -Train the dealership staff on company policies, processes and systems like sales processes, DMS, etc.
- -Team Manning
- -Plan and execute BTL activities at the dealerships to enhance retails.
- -Monitor day-to-day functioning of the dealers and be the point of contact to resolve all queries pertaining to sales.
- -Coordinate closely with the service team to resolve all service-related issues

MARKETING & BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER HARD SHELL TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD JUNE 2015-MAY 2021

SPECIALITIES

- New Business Development, Account management, Database management, Client servicing, Upselling & Reselling, Market Research.
- Performance measurement for effective strategic decision making by senior leadership.
- Managing Key Client engagements, relationship building, end-to-end management of Market Research Assignments, Team Management
- Strategic Planning and presenting analysis reports and providing business recommendations based on the results.

Business Development- National & International Markets Handling end to end sales cycle: Prospecting, Positioning, Negotiations, Closure and Account management.

Developing market strategy.

Understand and map company's offerings with client needs / requirements.

Heading initiatives in selling technology solutions for Mobile applications, PHP and .NET. Also offering clients with CRM, ERP and complex workflow applications.

Presales – Preparing response of Tenders/Bids for Various Govt & Non-Gov Institutions (RFI/ RFP/RFQ/EOI/Tenders & Proposals), conceptualizing target approach and evaluating projects.

Managing Companies Product Development & Overseeing Marketing & Sales of Same.

Conducting Events Like Job Fairs & Virtual Recruitment Drives. Coordinating with Skill Development Agencies, State Rural Livelihood Missions, NSDC & State Development Mission for Various Events & Business Opportunities
Handle prospect client, conference calls, meetings,

presentations, demo, etc. .

Product Launch, Marketing & Sales Initiatives.

Regional Trade Marketing- North India Fujifilm India Pvt. Ltd

NOV 2010 - DEC 2014

Conceptualizing & implementing BTL marketing activities aligned with the business goals.

Handling & increasing the database of quality vendors in all regions.

Responsible for effective role out of Promotions / Channel Communication / Customer Interface Programs.

Developing Sales Guides / Presentations / Product Catalogues etc.

Production & market deployment of POP's /Posters / Banners / Display Stands / USP labels/ Sales Tools.

Implementation of promotion special displays, decorations in outlets like shop in shop etc.

Co-ordinate with the sales team for effective Product Displays in all the key focus outlets.

Coordinating with vendors, suppliers for printing and design of marketing collaterals.

Competition Updates / market reports / Management reports. Active involvement in all the strategic market development activities of the Management.

Sr. Marketing Executive Skull Candy India – MB Accessories

AUG 2009 - NOV 2010

Coordinate and plan all marketing initiatives with the Manager – Corporate Communication.

Plan, develop and coordinate advertising materials or related communication activities

Retail Marketing Support – Trade Marketing & in shop branding. Managing Printing and inventory for all marketing collaterals Coordinating with Advertising Agency, Printers, other communications, business associates, Media Agency, outdoor and event agencies -Vendor Management. Handling Promotional BTL activities.

Online Marketing – Social Media Marketing & Website management.

Keeping track and records of the budget as well as other expense and keep the department updated for same Activation – organizing events & promotions. Handling Public Relations via agency.

Executive Marketing Spencer's Retail Ltd.

JUN 2007 - JUL 2009

Brand and Sales promotions.

Liaison with Advertising, Print, Event Management, Creative & Market Research Agencies (Agency/Vendor Management). Store Launches & Promotions, Branding, Area mapping, research, making marketing strategies, Organize in & out-store activities & Events. Implementing pre/post promotional activities for brand building.

Formulate marketing strategies to help promote and drive traffic to stores.

Coordinating with Project, Operations, and IT Teams for all store launches.

Making the analysis report of all store's promoted items & MIS Reports.

A&P Recovery (Advertisement & Promotion Recovery) for Delhi. Plan and carry out SOP's offers and promotions, managing festival campaigns.

Management of all marketing related reports and marketing communications.

BTL Activities for Delhi Region retail stores.

Catchment study, Benchmarking & Store Branding. Ensuring maximum brand visibility for stores.

EDUCATION

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN BUSINESS MANAGEMENT FROM CENTRE FOR MANAGEMENT DEVELOPMENT (CMD) MODINAGAR (UP), (2005-07).

Bachelor of Computer Application

from DAAS, Dehradun, affiliated from MCRPV University, Bhopal 2004.

Intermediate

from DAV Public School, Dehradun, CBSE Board in 2000.

Matriculation

from DAV Public School, Dehradun, CBSE Board in 1998.

ABOUT ME

HAIL FROM: DEHRADUN, UTTARAKHAND

Marital Status: Married

Date of Birth: 28th March 1982